### **Personal Information**

## **Colin Henry Jenkins**

Derbyshire,UK

#### Overview

I have over 20 years' experience of IT Administration, Support, Management and Project Management gained in the IT, Health, Legal, Railway, Media, FMCG and Utilities sectors, working with blue chip companies such as Cisco, the Law Society, the BBC, Railtrack, Silver Spoon (British Sugar plc) and PowerGen.

I am currently manager of the Derbyshire field engineering team for Arden & GEM CSU and its customers. The team provide 2<sup>nd</sup> line support to end users at numerous hospital, CCG and GP sites across Derbyshire and the immediate surrounds including desktop & laptop PCs, printers, remote server and network equipment.

Previous roles have included interim management/team leader positions, replacing staff seconded onto major projects. This has bought its own challenges, including the steep learning curve to learn how the business works and where IT fits in, and taking on the management of staff during what can be a very uncertain time for IT personnel. I am experienced in managing teams/projects with values of up to £4m and up to 20 professionals, from internal and external sources.

# **Certification & Training**

VMware Certified Professional

Microsoft Certified Professional

#### **Education**

The Open University

BSc (Honours) Computing & IT and a second subject

Eliesha Training/Arden GEM

CMI Level 5 Certificate in Management and Leadership

Southampton Institute of Higher Education

HND Mechanical Engineering (Marine)

### **Career History**

North of England Commissioning Support Unit (AGEM).

Chesterfield Oct 2017 – present Permanent

## **Senior Infrastructure Support Engineer**

I am responsible for ensuring the smooth running of CCG, GP and external resources to ensure the day-to-day and project work is undertaken within SLA.

#### Arden & Greater East Midlands Commissioning Support Unit (AGEM).

Chesterfield Sep 2015 - Sep 2017 Permanent

### **IT Field Engineering Team Manager**

Managing a team of 13 field engineers and two senior engineers providing 2<sup>nd</sup> line support across Derbyshire with outposts in Nottinghamshire & Leicestershire. There are approximately 10,000 users with the area covered. I am responsible for ensuring the timely resolution of incidents and problems, documentation of root causes and implementation of remedies. I am also responsible managing team and external resources to ensure the day-to-day and project work is undertaken within SLA.

I am also responsible for managing personal and team development and performance including absence management and mentoring. Undertake PDRs and one-to-one meetings with the team on a regular basis. I provide technical escalation support to the team members where necessary.

#### Core duties include:

- Workong with other service management functions to ensure effective operation of the change management function and the consistency of procedures.
- Contributing to the development of the organisation's strategic plans, including the creative use of information and communications technology.
- Investigates and develops innovative methods of exploiting the use of IT, to the benefit of the organisation and the community.
- Participates in strategic groups and facilitates focus groups and other 'ideas generators'.
- Works with business strategists and innovators to help them understand the opportunities that technology can provide
- Identifies and manages resources needed for the planning, development and delivery
  of specified information and communications systems services and products. Takes
  full responsibility for all aspects of career development for subordinate staff.

#### Arden & Greater East Midlands Commissioning Support Unit.

Chesterfield July 2013 - Sep 2015 Permanent

#### IT Technician (Server Team)

Part of a team providing infrastructure support to the Derbyshire CCG's; Derbyshire Health Care Foundation Trust and other NHS organisations within the AGEM geographical area. My primary areas of responsibility were virtualisation using VMware ESXi servers & VMware vCenter, server hardening and updates (WSUS) and web filtering using Websense.

#### Recent tasks include:

- Planning the upgrade from vCenter 4.1 to 5.5
- Migration of the web filter from Surf Control to Websense 7.7 including simplification and consolidation of the policies to take account of the new system
- Upgrading to the VMware estate from vCenter 3.5 to vCenter 4.1 with SRM.
- Implementing a WSUS solution for the Microsoft server estate and undertaking server hardening procedures to comply with NHS standards.

Day-to-day work includes 2<sup>nd</sup> & 3<sup>rd</sup> line resolution of issues logged by users and undertaking tasks as part of on-going work packages and projects.

Responsible for managing my own workload utilising standard tools, including LANDesk call logging system. Reporting to section leader and IT manager as required.

#### **Derbyshire Community Health Services (DCHS).**

Chesterfield November 2007 – June 2013 Permanent

#### IT Technician (Server Team)

Job role as above, TUPE'd into Arden & GEM CSU.

Derby City PCT.

Chesterfield March 2005 – November 2007 Permanent

#### IT Officer

Part of a team providing IT support to Derbyshire County Primary Care Trust (North) covering the PCT HQ, 7 hospitals and 60 GP practices: including desktop hardware and software, server, LAN WAN and telecom support.

#### Sept 2004 - March 2005.

Whilst looking for a new role I was actively updating my PC skills, learning about Windows XP and 2003 Server in order to keep abreast with current developments. Following a change in personal circumstances I was employed for the first three months of 2005 as a street sweeper with Derbyshire Dales District Council whilst continuing to look for more suitable positions.

### The Silver Spoon Company.

Peterborough October 2003 – July 2004

Fixed term contract

#### Interim IT Team Leader

Manage the day-to-day activities of the Silver Spoon IT (SSIT) Team supporting key Business applications. The SSIT team comprised 10 people, some of whom were seconded to the Peoplesoft JDE project. The remaining staff provide front line support and administration of Silver Spoon specific applications, e.g. Futurmaster, Preactor & Opus. General IT support (desktop and infrastructure) is provided by ISD, the British Sugar IT department.

- Detailed analysis of business processes & issues to ensure effectiveness of support provision and/or project scope.
- Day to day management of issues and team workload, including coaching and review processes.
- Management of Silver Spoon systems and third party support,
- Full cycle project delivery including planning, risk assessment, performance monitoring and reporting Manage resources to ensure consistent project & support provision.
- Develop relationships with internal customers and third party providers.

The Law Society of England and Wales.

**Leamington Spa** April 2003 – July 2003 Contract

#### **Application Support Team Leader**

Manage the day-to-day activities of the Business Application Support Team based in Leamington Spa, supporting key business applications using on Siebel and SER FlowWare. I managed two staff that provide front line support and administration. (Temporary contract to cover secondment)

- Monitor Remedy call system to ensure all problem and request calls are allocated correctly.
- Ensure support provision is carried out within the terms of SLA's and Service Charter agreements.
- Provide technical input and support to development projects on both systems.
- Act as liaison between the business and 3<sup>rd</sup> party service providers for support and development.
- Carry out all personnel duties including appraisal, coaching, and training.

The Law Society of England and Wales.

Redditch, Leamington Spa & London March 2002 – March 2003

Fixed term contract

## **Business Application Support Manager**

Manage and develop the implementation of the business application support regime, including responsibility for front line administration, support, upgrade and maintenance of key business application, both transaction and web based. Additionally I provide technical consultancy for both the IT and telecommunications infrastructure.

I managed a team of 12 people across three locations in the Midlands and London, which involved regular travel between sites. Specific duties include:

- Be the Society's in-house expert on business application support (both transaction and web).
- Ensure any IT component of business change includes a robust and cost effective application and infrastructure support service.
- Managing the provision of internal front-line business application administration, ensuring there is no unnecessary overlap with existing internal or external service provision.
- Managing the development and provision of business data reports, management information and statistical information using various reporting tools.
- Managing the provision of operational upgrade and enhancement programmes for key business applications.
- Managing the support of the Information Compliance Manager with regard to data and IT infrastructure security.
- Manage and motivate a team of business application support professionals, ensuring that all personnel matters are carried out in sympathy with the Society's personnel handbook, including appraisals, recruitment, training and development.

#### April 2001 - March 2002.

I took time out to update my skills in the internet environment by working to develop an RDBMS based web site dedicated to providing information for tourists to the Peak District National Park. This has involved learning various web technologies including HTML, PHP & XML and has also allowed me to update my RDBMS skills using both MySQL and ORACLE on LINUX.

### Cisco Systems Inc.

Uxbridge July 2000 – April 2001 Contract

### **EMEA Extranet Project Manager**

- Management and co-ordination of multiple projects for the provision of secure extranet links to Cisco partners within the EMEA region.
- Co-ordinate the development and maintenance of web based extranet site information, including MS Access database and web design.
- Management of resources for individual projects.
- Part of the three theatre team (EMEA, US & AsiaPac) monitoring future technology developments and their impact on Extranet.
- Manage the continual upgrade process for EMEA extranet software and hardware.
- Manage the regular provision of metric data to Cisco Business Sponsors for performance and capacity planning of extranet links.
- Development of processes and procedures for this relatively new team.
- Monitor Clarify call system to ensure expedient resolution of operational and project tickets raised by external and internal customers.

I was working on projects in Belgium, Ireland, Italy, The Netherlands & UK and had successfully completed projects in Belgium (1), France (2), Ireland (2), The Netherlands (5), UK (6)

#### **PowerGen**

**Nottingham** Aug 1999 – July 2000 Contract

#### Infrastructure Project Manager

- Management and co-ordination of multiple projects within three separate programmes of work.
- Liaison with Business Streams to produce development and implementation plans

Management of resources for individual projects

Responsible for central/corporate projects, including the standardisation of router protocols and network frame types across PowerGen and a replacement Corporate RAS solution.

Successfully completed the roll-out of internet access to the desktop across the company ahead of schedule; the migration of 3500 users from MS Mail to Lotus Notes within project timescales and a Year 2000 project to ensure compliance of approximately 200 PC's within PowerGen's IT department.

#### Railtrack

London July 1997 – May 1999 Contract.

# Technical Project Manager (Jan 1999)

Development and maintenance of project plans, budgets and resourcing needs, facilitating the definition of customer requirements and project scope. Also liaising with other teams and departments within Railtrack Information Systems (RTIS), external suppliers and the customer to ensure timely delivery and compliance with Railtrack, RTIS and statuary requirements and procedures. Major projects completed:

- The move of the Railtrack East Anglia Zone HQ to refurbished offices in central London.
- The move of the West Coast Route Modernisation (WCRM) project into refurbished offices at Euston Station, London.

Both projects involved the specification of LAN, WAN and desktop infrastructure. I was additionally involved managing the process of porting various legacy applications to NT, ensuring that they continued to function as required. Additionally, as the WCRM Project was a partnership between Railtrack, GEC Alstom and Union Switch & Signal (US&S), a US based company, it was necessary to specify LAN infrastructure capable of allowing all three companies involved access to their own virtual private networks (VPN) whilst allowing secure data transfer via ftp and Lotus Notes.

### **Local IT Manager (Aug 1998)**

Following a reorganisation of the Local IT management structure I was asked to take on the role of Local IT Manager (LITM) for Railtrack's HQ function. I was a focus for the IS support function and a key interface between RTIS and its customers, establishing and maintaining links between internal and external customers and managing the provision of an effective IS support through management and development of my team of 25 technical and administrative personnel. Tasks included:

- Delivery of a comprehensive support service to agreed Service Level Agreements (SLA).
- Manage and report performance to the customer and RTIS management.
- Ensure that support is delivered within the framework of the RTIS and Railtrack standards.
- Manage the IT budget for Railtrack Headquarters.
- Manage the recruitment, development and training of permanent and contract staff.
- Procurement of IT equipment and services for Railtrack Headquarters.

#### **Local Technical Manager (May 1998)**

I was responsible for the day-to-day operational running of the Railtrack HQ IT Support function. Tasks included:

- Management of the IS Infrastructure Team for Railtrack HQ, including Novell, NT and UNIX 1servers and LAN/WAN systems.
- Management of third party service providers.
- Identification of problem areas within the network infrastructure and provide assistance to Technical Services in their resolution.
- Manage provision of in-house and external training for team members where necessary.
- Manage the provision of application and infrastructure monitoring and reporting to RTIS senior management and strategy team.
- Provision of expert technical support to the local IT Support Team.

#### Senior Technical Specialist (Oct 1997)

Following successful completion of the HQ Migration Project, I moved into the HQ IT Support Team providing infrastructure and desktop support to the Euston Square offices. Main tasks included:

- Provision of second line desktop support to the HQ user base for both shrink-wrapped and bespoke applications.
- Infrastructure support and maintenance to Railtrack Standards including the security policy.
- Provide mentoring/training to other team members on bespoke railway systems and applications.

### **Network Analyst**

The HQ Migration Project centralised Railtrack's HQ functions into a new building at Euston Square.

#### **BBC**

**London** Sept 1996 – July 1997 Permanent

**Server Manager.** Server management / troubleshooting for BBC Television Centre. (Novell, NT4, UNIX)

#### **BR Research**

Derby Aug 1989 – Aug 1996 Permanent

**LAN Manager (Sept 1995)** - Management and support of the BR Research LAN infrastructure and desktops for 400 users. (Novell, NT 3.51 & 4.0, UNIX (HP-UX, AIX, Sun) Win 3.11/95)

**Senior Engineer (Oct 1994)** - Network and user administration for the Projects Group. (Novell, AIX, Win 3.11/95) (150 users)

**Assistant Consultant (Apr 1994)** - Combined engineering consultancy work with administration of the Projects Group LAN. (150 users)

**Engineering Assistant (Jun 1990)** - Developing train performance programs using AIX/Oracle. Maintenance of legacy mainframe FORTRAN code. Administration of LAN infrastructure (100 users).

**Senior Technical Officer (Aug 1989)** - Train performance simulation using mainframe programs. Development of PC based macro applications.

#### Skill profile

#### Management skills:

Performance management both informal and with structured process

Mentoring and development of staff

Project management

Delegation

Customer liaison

Ability to translate between technical and non-technical teams.

**Technical skills:** (Primarily server infrastructure and virtualization/cloud computing).

Virtualisation: VMware vCenter & ESXi 6, 5.5, 4.1, 3.5; Hyper V.

Server: Windows Server 2012 R2, 2008 R2, Linux.

Workstation: Windows 10, 8.1, 7, XP, AIX, HP-UX, Linux (CentOS, Ubuntu, Red Hat,

SUSE).

Software: MS Office to 2016 & Office 365, general personal productivity software, MS

Project, Visio.

Database: MS SQL Server; MySQL, Oracle 10

Web: HTML, PHP, Perl, DHTML, XML, Java, FrontPage, Dreamweaver.

Scripting: Windows PowerShell, VBS, PHP, PERL.

LAN/WAN: Cisco routers & switches, TCP/IP, dhcp, dns. Juniper firewall.